# Lisa Cunningham

#### EDITOR/COPYWRITER

#### CONTACT

(404) 953-0770

Atlanta, GA 🗣

lisa.awesome@gmail.com @

#### SKILLS

Attention to Detail
Deadline-Focused and
Results-Driven
Communication
Planning & Organization
Positive Attitude
Grammatical Accuracy
Analytical Skills
Logical Thinking

#### EDUCATION

### MASTER OF ARTS IN ENGLISH

University of West Georgia

Carrollton, GA

## BACHELOR OF ARTS IN ENGLISH

University of West Georgia

Carrollton, GA

#### PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

As an eleven-year veteran of academia, I have realized that my passion for grammar and precision would best serve an employer who values communication, contributing towards a common goal, and a deadline-focused approach to tasks. Freelance editing for the past ten years has been the work I most enjoyed and which I felt made the most positive difference.

#### EXPERIENCE

#### **INSTRUCTOR OF ENGLISH**

WEST GEORGIA TECHNICAL COLLEGE | 01/2009 - PRESENT

I create syllabi, lesson plans, scoring metrics, and shared online course environments for every level of our English courses while instructing approximately 144 students each semester (with an average pass rate of 96%). My committee work focuses on restructuring our courses to meet statewide curricula and to create an excellent standard base course design for each class.

- Composed and edited the departmental handbook and training documents for teaching English courses.
- Constructed and maintained the online course environments of 6 upperlevel literature courses for college-wide implementation.
- Edited and prepared for publication VOICES, the college creative writing magazine the only one published by an American technical college.

#### **EDITOR**

FREELANCE | 01/2009 - PRESENT

As a freelance editor, I have worked in numerous contexts to refine writing into precise and error-free language, as in the following recent work:

- The Employee Handbook and the Instructional Handbook for New Students (composed and edited)
  - THE SPACE MOVEMENT STUDIO | FEBRUARY 2015
- Statewide Standards for Teaching English, K-12
  - GEORGIA DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION | APRIL 2016
- Ecofamilism: Women, Religion, and Environmental Protection in Taiwan (full book copyedit for publication)

WAN-LI HO (AUTHOR), EMORY UNIVERSITY | JANUARY 2016

# Lisa Cunningham

#### EDITOR/COPYWRITER

#### CONTACT

(404) 953-0770

Atlanta, GA Q

lisa.awesome@gmail.com

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Windows OS & Mac OS

Microsoft Word

Microsoft Excel

Microsoft Outlook

Course Management Software

(Blackboard, Angel, etc.)

Email Management

## PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

#### **PRESENTATIONS**

Presented my research at over 15 national and international conferences

#### **INVITED SPEAKING**

Guest-taught philosophy, psychology, and biology lectures, as well as chairing panels and roundtables at professional conferences

#### EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)

#### **INSTRUCTOR OF ENGLISH (PART-TIME)**

GEORGIA STATE UNIVERSITY | 08/2012 - 12/2016

UNIVERSITY OF WEST GEORGIA | 01/2010 - 06/2013

As a part-time instructor, I taught two courses per semester as the instructor of record. I designed the assignments, course lessons, reading schedules, and assessments, and I worked closely with all department faculty to develop and revise assessment standards for the English department.

- Graduate Teaching Fellow
- Tutored business and accounting students in the Writing Center.

#### PUBLICATIONS

#### **CHAPTERS CONTAINED IN EDITED COLLECTIONS**

- "'Do Not Read the Latin': The Summoning Diary in Horror Film." *Terrifying Texts: Essays on Books of Good and Evil in Horror Cinema*. Washington, DC: Rowman & Littlefield, July 2018.
- "Les Paumees du Petit Matin: A View of Female Violence." Lost Girls: The Phantasmagorical Cinema of Jean Rollin. Canada: Spectacular Optical, August 2017.
- "Queerness and the Undead Female Monster." The Laughing Dead: The Horror-Comedy Film from Bride of Frankenstein to Zombieland. Ed. Cynthia Miller and Bow Van Riper. Washington, DC: Rowman & Littlefield, April 2016.
- "Violent Nymphs: Vampire and Vigilante Children in Contemporary Cinema." Monstrous Children and Childish Monsters: Essays on Cinema's Holy Terrors. Ed. Sean Moreland and Markus Bohlmann. Jefferson, NC: McFarland, 2015.
- "'What's in the Basket?': Sexualized and Sexualizing Violence in Frank Henenlotter's *Basket Case.*" *Screening the Dark Side of Love: From Euro-Horror to American Cinema*. Ed. Karen Ritzenhoff and Karen Randell. New York: Palgrave Macmillan, 2012.